Section 1. You
will hear a young man phoning a
town's youth council.
First, you have some time to
look at questions, 1:00 to 5:00.
You will see that there is an example
that has been done for you.
On this occasion, only the conversation
relating to this will be played
first.
Good morning, Youth Council. Caroline
speaking. Ohh. Hello. I'm interested in
standing for election to the Youth
Council and I was told to give
you a call. That's good. Could I
have your name, please? Yes, it's Roger
Brown. Thank you.
The young man's name is Roger
Brown, so Brown has been written
in the space.
Now we shall begin. You
should answer the questions as you listen
because you will not hear the recording a
second time.
Listen carefully and answer
questions 1:00 to 5:00.
Good morning, Youth Council. Caroline
speaking. Ohh. Hello. I'm interested in
standing for election to the Youth
Council, and I was told to give
you a call. That's good. Could I
have your name, please? Yes, it's Roger
Brown. Thank you. I'm Caroline, the Youth
Council administrator. So do you know
much about what the council does? Roger,
I've talked to Stephanie. I think she's
the chair of the council. That's right.
And she told me a lot about it, how
it's a way for young people to discuss
local issues, for example, and make
suggestions to the town council. That's
what made me interested. Well,
let me take down some of your details.
First of all, how old are you? You
know, the council is for young people
aged from 13 to 18. I've just turned
18. And where do you live, Roger? Well,
that's a bit complicated. At the moment
I'm looking for a flat to rent.
Yeah, so I'm in a hostel
from Monday to Friday. I go
back to my parents place at
the weekend. OK, so where's the
best place to send you some
information about the council? Ohh. To
my parents address please. That's 17
Buckley Street, BUCK. Leigh
St. Stamford, Lincolnshire, though
you don't really need
the county. Ohh I
know Stanford, it's a
lovely town. And what's
the post code? PE9
7QT right?Thank you. So are
you working here or are you a student? I
started studying at the university a
couple of weeks ago and I've got a part
time job for a few hours a week. What
do you do? Well, I've done several
different things. I've just finished a
short term contract as a Courier and now
I'm working as a waiter. And one of
the big hotels? Uh-huh. That can't leave
you much time for studying. Ohh. It's not
too bad. I managed to fit it all in.
What are you studying? My ambition is to
go into parliament eventually, so my
major subject is politics. That's partly
why I think the Youth Council is
important and want to be a part of it.
And I suppose you're also taking a minor
subject, aren't you? I know a lot of
people study economics too. I chose
history. To be honest, I'm not finding it
as interesting as I expected.
Before you hear the rest of the phone
call, you have some time to look at
questions 6 to 10.
Now listen and answer questions
6 to 10.
OK, so with your studying and your
part time job, do you have time
for any other interests or hobbies? Well,
I spent quite a lot of time
cycling both around town to get to
university and to work, and also long
distance from here to London for
instance. That's pretty impressive.
Anything. For relaxation I'm also keen on
the cinema, I used to go at least once
a week, but I can't manage to go so
often now, right. Are you sure you'll
have enough time for the youth council?
Yes, I've worked out that I can afford to
reduce my hours at work and that will
make the time. So is there any particular?
Aspect of the Youth Council's work that
appeals to you, Roger. Well, my sister
is blind, so I'm particularly interested
in working with disabled young people to
try and improve the quality of their
lives. That's great. Well, the best way
to get involved is to be nominated
by some people who you know. Right.
Can you tell me how to set
about organizing that? You should talk to
Jeffrey, our elections officer. I can
arrange a meeting in the council office
with him if you like. Yes, please.
He'll be here next Monday, if that
suits you. That's the 14th, isn't it?
Yes, I can manage. Late afternoon, would
you like to suggest a time he
generally leaves around 5:30? Well, would
430 be OK? My last class finishes
at 4:00, so I'd have plenty of
time to get to your office, right?
That's fine. Oh, and could I have
a phone number we can contact you
on?Yes, my mobile
numbers 07788136711. Thank you.
Well, we'll look forward
to seeing you next
week. Thanks very much.
Good bye. Bye.
That is the end of Section 1.
You now have half a minute to check
your answers.
Now turn to Section 2.